<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Frog.care</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Frog.care</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:53:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Frogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/choosing_frogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 16:41:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/choosing_frogs/</guid>
      <description>Choosing Frogs # TL;DR # Excellent beginner frogs:&#xA;Dendrobates leucomela Dendrobates tinctorius Dendrobates auratus Epipedobates anthonyi What looks the coolest? # Browse lots of great frog pictures here: http://www.dendrowiki.org/alle.html&#xA;Can you get one captive bred? # Captive bred frogs are generally healthier in captivity as they have already adapted to life in a vivarium and are dramatically less at risk of bringing diseases along with them that they might otherwise pick up in the wild.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/feeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 16:15:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/feeding/</guid>
      <description>Feeding Dart Frogs # TL;DR # Frogs: 3 days a week. Froglets: 5-7 days a week. Melanogaster or hydei fruit flies depending on frog size Dust flies with calcium + d3 vitamins every feeding, vitamin A at least once a month How to dust flies https://youtu.be/Q9PkDXLK13A?si=azksV1dVeihP2gvj What do I feed? # Frogs eat fruitflies and springtails (which are usually just part of the clean up crew rather than fed directly).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vivarium Size</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/vivarium_size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:47:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/vivarium_size/</guid>
      <description>Vivarium Size # TL;DR # For 2-3 of most dart frogs, 18x18x24&amp;quot;.&#xA;Medium and large frogs # (1-2&amp;quot;, 2.5-5cm, eg. Dendrobates [tinctorius, leucomela, auratus], Oophaga, large Ameerega such as bassleri)&#xA;2-3 frogs: 18x18x18&amp;quot;, 45x45x45cm 2-3 arboreal frogs: 18x18x24&amp;quot;, 45x45x60cm. Even &amp;ldquo;terrestrial frogs&amp;rdquo; such as D. tinctorius and D. leucomelas are known to climb all available space in a 24&amp;quot; tall vivarium and will be happy to have it. Small frogs # (&amp;lt;1&amp;quot;, eg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temperature</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 20:44:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/temperature/</guid>
      <description>Temperature # TL;DR # Most dart frogs thrive at 70°F (21°C). They can tolerate up to 80°F (26°C) and down to 65°F (18°C) for short periods of time. 85°F (29°C) and above is potentially fatal.&#xA;Heat the Room # The best way to manage vivarium temperatures is by heating the room. If you absolutely can&amp;rsquo;t heat the room with space heaters or other ambient solutions, a heating mat linked with a thermostat can work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aggression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/aggression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 19:38:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/aggression/</guid>
      <description>Aggression / Territoriality # TL;DR # Aggression can occur in any species of dart frogs. Look for signs of aggression between frogs and be prepared to separate them if it occurs. Aggression often takes the form of wrestling with territorial calls from males being forced and staccatto than mating calls.&#xA;Do well in groups # Dendrobates auratus Dendrobates leucomela Epipedobates anthonyi Phyllobates (all species) Ranitomeya (all species) Ameerega (all species) Do not do well in groups # Dendrobates tinctorius females are territorial, limit groups to breeding pair or two males, one female Oophaga (all species) males are territorial, small groups can be ok but do best in breeding pairs Videos of aggressive behavior # https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Features</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/water_feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 17:50:40 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/water_feature/</guid>
      <description>Water Features # TL;DR # Don&amp;rsquo;t include a water feature unless you know exactly what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, which probably means you don&amp;rsquo;t need this information.&#xA;Water features are complicated, prone to problems and take away from much needed surface area in an already constrained space and are generally more complicated and risky than the aesthetics make them worth. Most dart frog keepers do not include more than a small, shallow dish of water for their frogs to soak in (sometimes with a calcium clay mixture).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humidity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/humidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 18:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/humidity/</guid>
      <description>Humidity # TL;DR # Keep humidity above 70% for most dart frogs while ensuring there&amp;rsquo;s enough ventilation to allow leaf litter to dry.&#xA;Ventilation # Many plants want to dry out to some degree between misting cycles or their roots and leaves may rot. To enable this, ensure there is enough crossflow ventilation in the vivarium. Most front-opening vivariums have vents under the doors. Because heat rises, a small amount of cross-flow ventilation will occur as long as there are vents on the lid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Mix Dart Frogs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/dont_mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 18:20:10 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/dont_mix/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t Mix Dart Frogs # TL;DR # It&amp;rsquo;s common for beginner frog keepers to want to get one of each of their favorite frogs for their enclosure, but this is generally not a good idea. Mixing dart frogs carries significant risks, however, so if you want more than one species or locale, only do so if you can keep a separate vivarium for each type.&#xA;Problem 1: Frogs will hybridize when breeding # Many dart frogs are closely related enough that they will hybridize (for example D.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 15:03:53 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Contributing # Spotted an error? See an opportunity to improve an answer? Want to add a whole new article? Please do!&#xA;Content on Frog.care is intended to be easy to copy and paste to supply as answers to commonly asked questions in various communities such as Facebook groups, Discords, MeWe chats, and others text heavy places. When editing content, try to keep answers as simple as possible with links to sources for more involved, long-form content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 18:15:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/license/</guid>
      <description>License # Content on this website is licensed under Creative Commons Attributuion-Noncommercial-Sharealike 4.0 International&#xA;Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International # Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License By exercising the Licensed Rights (defined below), You accept and agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International Public License (&amp;quot;Public License&amp;quot;). To the extent this Public License may be interpreted as a contract, You are granted the Licensed Rights in consideration of Your acceptance of these terms and conditions, and the Licensor grants You such rights in consideration of benefits the Licensor receives from making the Licensed Material available under these terms and conditions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
